Grover B. Proctor, Jr. papers, Inclusive: 1961-2013, undated, Bulk: 1975-1993
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials
Grover B. Proctor, Jr. papers
Inclusive: 1961-2013, undated, Bulk: 1975-1993
Baylor University, Baylor Collections of Political Materials http://www.baylor.edu/lib/bcpm/
21
Proctor, Grover B., Jr.
3 document boxes and 1 oversized box.
This collection consists of research collected and articles written by Grover B. Proctor, Jr., a prominent researcher on the assassination of President John F. Kennedy.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Dr. Grover B. Proctor, Jr. attended Broughton High School in Raleigh, North Carolina from 1966 to 1969. Proctor then enrolled in the University of North Carolina-Chapel Hill where he earned a bachelor’s degree in communications in 1973. Much of Proctor’s professional career has been spent in academia. He served as an Associate Dean for Northwood University in Midland, Michigan from 1985 to 2008, and is currently graduate faculty at Walden University. He earned a doctorate in education from Wayne State University in 2001.
Proctor began researching the assassination of President John F. Kennedy in 1974. He has since written several articles and presented various lectures on his research. One of his most prominent works focuses on the “Raleigh Call”, an alleged phone call that Lee Harvey Oswald made to John Hurt, a former military counterintelligence officer in Raleigh, North Carolina, before Oswald was killed.
Scope and Content
Materials in this collection reflect Grover Proctor's research into the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. While the scope of the collection ranges from the early 1960s to 2013, most of Proctor’s research and writing dates back from the mid-1970s to the early 1990s.
Proctor collected several publication types including articles, books, magazines, journals, newspapers, and newsletters. Many of the articles found in the collection were written by Proctor himself. Of particular importance is Proctor's "Raleigh Call" materials. These relate to his work on Lee Harvey Oswald who allegedly made a phone call from a Dallas jail to a former military counterintelligence officer in Raleigh, North Carolina. There are also materials pertaining to Oliver Stone’s 1991 film, JFK, and a substantial run of a JFK-related journal titled The Third Decade.
The materials in this collection are, overall, in good condition.
Arrangement
The Grover B. Proctor, Jr. papers have been processed by Poage Library staff in the past, as recently as 2014. Thus, a previous finding aid and inventory existed prior to this 2021 processing.
The original organization imposed on the collection has largely been maintained. The lone series, Series I. JFK Research Materials, is organized alphabetically by material type.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the W. R. Poage Legislative Library in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 21. Acquired 2011-11-03
Related Resources
Items in related collections
Gus Russo papers, Inclusive: 1932-2006, Bulk: 1953-1998
Dick Russell papers, Inclusive: 1924-2011, undated, Bulk: 1964-2003, undated
Don Grisham collection, Inclusive: 1947-1964, Bulk: 1963-1964
Theresa Seay papers, Inclusive: 1865-2008, undated, Bulk: 1960-2002
Related references
Assassination Archives and Research Center. "Dr. Grover B. Proctor, Jr. - The Raleigh Call and the Fingerprints of Intelligence." Accessed December 16, 2021.
"The JFK Assassination: Articles by Dr. Grover B. Proctor, Jr." Accessed December 16, 2021.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Assassination.; Oswald, Lee Harvey.
Subjects
Conspiracy theories.
Genres
Articles.; Books.; Newsletters.; Periodicals.; Research notes.
- JFK Research Materials, 1961-2013, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  Series I. JFK Research Materials, the only series in the collection, contains research materials that Grover Proctor gathered or created as a result of his investigation into the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. The authors of the articles are noted in the folder titles and any folders that deal specifically with Proctor's research on the "Raleigh Call" are noted as well. Overall, the series is in good condition and is arranged alphabetically.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Compact disk (CD); Digital video disk (DVD); Video home system (VHS) tapes
  - Advertisement, “Eyewitness to History: The Kennedy Assassination as Seen by Howard Brennan”, Howard Brennan, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Analysis, “The Cuban Crisis and the Chinese-Indian Border War”, Andrew Dapondes, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Article, “30th Anniversary Book Review”, “The Saginaw News”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1993 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Article, “Anatomy of a Murder: Who Killed JFK? 25 Years of Doubt”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1988 November 24 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 3)
  - Article, “Facts Behind the Making of This Film”, “Executive Action”, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Article, “JFK: Questions Remain 20 Years Later”, “Midland Daily News”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1983 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Article, “Lane’s ‘Good Yarn’ Blames CIA for Killing JFK”, “The Saginaw News”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1991 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Article, “Larry Howard: A Man Under Fire”, “The Saginaw News”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Article, “Not If, But Who: The Credibility of a Conspiracy”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1981 April 16 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 4)
  - Article, “Oswald Did Not Act Alone, ‘JFK’ Advisor Maintains”, “The Saginaw News”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1991 December 21 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Article, “Sins of Commission”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1992 January 9 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 5)
  - Article, “Smoking Guns”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1991 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Article, “The JFK Assassination Conspiracy: Good-Bye to All That”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr. and James R. Black, 1995 November 9 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 6)
  - Article, “The Kennedy Assassination: Where Are We Twenty-Five Years Later”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., Raleigh Call, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Article, “The Phone Call That Never Was”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., Raleigh Call (1 of 2), 1980 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Article, “The Phone Call That Never Was”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., Raleigh Call (2 of 2), 1980 July 17 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 7)
  - Article, “The Raleigh Call”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1980-2004 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Article, “They Killed My President” and “Oswald’s Raleigh Call”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1980 July 24 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 8)
  - Article, “Thirty Years After the Tragedy: The American Odyssey”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1993 November (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Article, “Will We Ever Know Who Killed JFK?” and “Ruby, Oswald and the Unholy Alliance”, “Spectator”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1979 September 12-19 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 9)
  - Articles, “Jackdaw Special”, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Articles and Correspondence, Oliver Stone Film, “JFK”, 1991, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bibliography, John F. Kennedy Assassination, circa 1988 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Book, “Dr. Mary’s Monkey”, Edward T. Haslam, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Book, “Inside the JFK Conspiracy”, Dan H. Christian, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Book, “Nomenclature of an Assassination”, William Torbitt, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Book, “Rush to Judgment”, Mark Lane, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Brochures, JFK Assassination Information Center (1 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Brochures, JFK Assassination Information Center (2 of 2), undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Brochures, The Sixth Floor Museum, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Catalog, “Prevailing Winds Research 1992” (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - CD and DVD, Interview with Grover B. Proctor, Jr., JFK Assassination, 2013 November (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 1)
  - Congressional Petitions, Citizens Commission of Inquiry, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence, Paul Hoch, Raleigh Call, 1970-2000 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence and Order Forms, November 22nd Society, Warren Graham, 1984, undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Essay, “An Historical Analysis of Oliver Stone’s ‘JFK’”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1991 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Evidence and Research, Bernard Fensterwald, Raleigh Call, 1968-1989, undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Flyer, “The JFK Assassination”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Flyer, “The JFK Assassination: 25 Years Later”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., 1988 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Flyer, “Tumultuous Times: Examining Events that Shaped the 1960s”, Wake County (North Carolina) Public Libraries, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Hearings, Select Committee on Assassinations, 95th Congress, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Hints and Allegations, John Hurt, Raleigh Call, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Index, “The Raleigh Call”, 2012 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Description of Contents, undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 2, Issue 1, 1985 November (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 2, Issue 2, 1986 January (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 2, Issue 4, 1986 May (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 2, Issue 6, 1986 September (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 3, Issue 1, 1986 November (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 3, Issue 3, 1987 March (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 3, Issue 4, 1987 May (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 3, Issue 5, 1987 July (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 3, Issue 6, 1987 September (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 1, 1987 November (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 2, 1988 January (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 3, 1988 March (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 4, 1988 May (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 5, 1988 July (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 4, Issue 6, 1988 September (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 1, 1988 November (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 2, 1989 January (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 3, 1989 March (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 4, 1989 May (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 5, 1989 July (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 5, Issue 6, 1989 September (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 6, Issue 1, 1989 November (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 6, Issue 2, 1990 January (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 6, Issue 3, 1990 March (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 6, Issue 4, 1990 May (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 6, Issue 5, 1990 July (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 7, Issue 5, 1991 July (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 8, Issue 1, 1991 November (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Journal, “The Third Decade”, Volume 8, Issue 5, 1992 July (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Magazine, “Newsweek”, “What JFK Meant to Us”, 1983 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Magazine, “People Weekly”, “Did One Man with One Gun Kill John F. Kennedy?”, 1975 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Magazine, “Texas Monthly”, “Oswald’s Ghost”, 1983 November (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Newsletter, “Clandestine America”, Assassination Information Bureau, 1971 September-October (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Newsletter, “Coverups!”, Number 17, 1984 July (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Newsletter, “November 22nd Society”, Volume 1, Issue 4, 1984 October (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Newsletter, “The Dorff Report”, Volume 1, Issue 1, 1990 February (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Newsletter, “The Dorff Report”, Volume 1, Issue 2, 1990 March (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Newsletter, “The Dorff Report”, Volume 1, Issue 3, 1990 April (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Newsletter, “The Entrepreneur”, Northwood of Michigan, 1991 November 7 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Newsletter, “Washington Watch”, Volume 2, Issue 28, 1974 December 1 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper Articles, Binder, 1964-2013 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (1 of 4), 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (2 of 4), 1975-1984 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (3 of 4), 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (4 of 4), 1975-1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (1 of 5), 1988-2012 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (2 of 5), 1988-2012 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (3 of 5), 1988-2012 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (4 of 5), 1988-2012 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notebook, Magazine Articles (5 of 5), 1988-2012 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Notes, Handwritten, undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Phone Directory, North Carolina, Hunt, Raleigh Call, 1961-1964 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Phone Slip, Dallas Jail, Raleigh Call, 1963 November 23 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Photographs, Dealey Plaza, undated (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Postcards, The Sixth Floor Museum, undated (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Production Notes, “JFK” Film, Warner Bros., 1991, undated (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Publication, “Four Dark Days in History: A Photo History of President Kennedy’s Assassination”, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Publication, “The Killing of a President: Dealey Plaza Memorial Edition”, Robert J. Groden and Diane J. Allen, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Report, “John Hurt Allegation”, Surrell Brady, Raleigh Call, undated (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Report, Select Committee on Assassinations, 94th Congress, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Report, Select Committee on Assassinations, 95th Congress, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Request for Materials, Assassination Archives and Research Center, Raleigh Call, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Research Notes, National Archives, 1988, undated (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Script, “Heard the Highway Calling”, Raleigh Call, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Transcript, “American Expose: Who Murdered JFK?”, 1988 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Transcript, “CBS Reports: Four Days in November”, 1988 November 17 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Transcript, “Who Shot President Kennedy”, PBS, 1988 November 15 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Updates, Assassination Archives and Research Center, 1988-1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - VHS Tape, “The JFK Assassination”, Grover B. Proctor, Jr., Freedom Seminar, Northwood Institute, 1988 July 28 (Box 4 OVZ, Folder 2)